<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ubuntu on Tips and Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ubuntu on Tips and Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright. Tips and Tutorials. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 14:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Alfresco Community Edition 5.1 in Ubuntu Server 14.04</title>
      <link>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/05/07/how-to-install-alfresco-community-edition-5.1-in-ubuntu-server-14.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/05/07/how-to-install-alfresco-community-edition-5.1-in-ubuntu-server-14.04/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will explain how to install Alfresco Community Edition 5.1 in Ubuntu Server 14.04. In this example, Ubuntu Server is a virtual machine made by VirtualBox.
Requirements  Ubuntu Server virtual machine with:  Two network adapters: NAT adapter (eth0) Host-only adapter (eth1) with a static IP address -&amp;gt; 192.168.56.101 Base memory: 4608 Mb 2 CPUs  Alfresco Community Edition binary file -&amp;gt; alfresco-community-installer-201604-linux-x64.bin  Check out how to install Ubuntu Server on VirtualBox to get ready a virtual machine to install Alfresco Community Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to connect to your MySQL database remotely</title>
      <link>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/05/02/how-to-connect-to-your-mysql-database-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/05/02/how-to-connect-to-your-mysql-database-remotely/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will explain how to connect remotely to MySQL database. In this example, MySQL server is installed in Ubuntu Server virtual machine with VirtualBox.
Requirements  Ubuntu Server virtual machine with MySQL:
 Two network adapters: NAT adapter (eth0) Host-only adapter (eth1) with a static IP address -&amp;gt; 192.168.56.101. Database name: mybb  MySQL client:
 Toad World   Expose MySQL server To expose MySQL to anything other than localhost you will have to expose the IP address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install MyBB on Ubuntu Server</title>
      <link>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/04/21/install-mybb-on-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/04/21/install-mybb-on-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will explain how to install MyBB in Ubuntu Server.
Requirements A Ubuntu Server virtual machine with:
 MySQL Apache FTP Samba  Check out these posts to get ready:
 How to install Ubuntu Server on VirtualBox Setting up a Virtual Web Server with VirtualBox, Apache, MySQL, FTP, Ubuntu, and Samba  Our virtual machine has two network adapters. The second one (eth1) is a host-only adapter with a static IP address -&amp;gt; 192.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Virtual Web Server with VirtualBox, Apache, MySQL, FTP, Ubuntu, and Samba</title>
      <link>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/04/17/setting-up-a-virtual-web-server-with-virtualbox-apache-mysql-ftp-ubuntu-and-samba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/04/17/setting-up-a-virtual-web-server-with-virtualbox-apache-mysql-ftp-ubuntu-and-samba/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will explain how to set up a Ubuntu Server virtual machine with:
 Apache FTP Samba  First, check out how to install Ubuntu Server on VirtualBox to get ready a virtual machine to test.
Our virtual machine has two network adapters. The second one (eth1) is a host-only adapter with a static IP address -&amp;gt; 192.168.56.101
Apache Web Server Apache Web Server needs to be running. The installation and configuration was indicated in the previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ubuntu Server 14.04.4 on VirtualBox</title>
      <link>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/04/15/install-ubuntu-server-14.04.4-on-virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 22:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dalanzg.github.io/tips-tutorials/posts/2016/04/15/install-ubuntu-server-14.04.4-on-virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will explain how to install Ubuntu Server on a virtual machine.
First, you need to have Ubuntu Server ISO file and VirtualBox installed.
 VirtualBox Ubuntu Server  Create a new virtual machine on VirtualBox by clicking on New.
Create new virtual machine  Select type and version of the virtual machine. In this case, Linux and Ubuntu (64-bits).
Select type and version of the virtual machine  Select the amount of memory (RAM).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>